Guide to the Paul Hartman papers, 1944-1993.
Hartman, Paul papers, 1944-1993.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Paul Hartman papers, 1944-1993.
14-22-3294
Paul Hartman, 1913-
2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, laboratory and course notebooks, talks, and publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, laboratory and course notebooks, talks, and publications, relating to Hartman's teaching career and the histories he wrote on the Materials Science Center and the Physics Dept. at Cornell University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Emeritus, School of Applied and Engineering Physics, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, laboratory and course notebooks, talks, and publications, relating to Hartman's teaching career and the histories he wrote on the Materials Science Center and the Physics Dept. at Cornell University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hartman, Paul, 1913-; Cornell University.--Faculty.; Cornell University. Dept. of Physics--History.; Cornell University. Dept. of Physics--Anecdotes.; Cornell University. Materials Science Center.
Subjects:
Physics--New York (State)--History.; Materials--Study and teaching.; Materials--Research.; Physics--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Notebooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Physics Dept. History
Series II. Hartman Material - Biographical Information and Publications
Series III. Correspondence
Series IV. Talks, Notes, Reports, Plans Concerning Various Topics
Series V. Photographs and Exhibit Material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Physics Dept. History
  - Dept. Reorganization - formation of LASSP, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Physics Dept. History (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Material Science Center History (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Physics ARPA Building, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Physics Dept. Minutes/Memos, 1946-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lab of Nuclear Studies - Circuit Manual, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II. Hartman Material - Biographical Information and Publications
  - Hartman Biographical material (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Publications by Hartman, 1950s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Publications by Hartman, 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dispersion Relations - Logothetis - by Hartman, no date (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Record of the Tribulations Gone Through in Naming the Dept. Chairman and the Reorganization of the Research of Rockefeller Hall - by Hartman, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - New Measurements of the Fluorescence Efficiency of Air Under Electron Bombardment - by Hartman, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Summary of Work Done with Group J-10 During 1973-1974 - by Hartman, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Report of Work Done on Focusing Febetron Electron Beam to Small Target - Hartman, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Early Experimental Work on Synchrotron Radiation - by Hartman, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - A Brief History Over the Formative First Decade and a Half of the Materials Science Center at Cornell - by Hartman, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Impact of the ARPA Program in the Area of Materials Science at CU - by Henri Sack and Paul Leurgans (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Future of Engineering Physics at Cornell - by H.S. Sack (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series III. Correspondence
  - Letter from Harley Howe to Newell Gingrich - concerns Howe's career, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence - letters to Hartman from former Physics Professors/Family, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Series IV. Talks, Notes, Reports, Plans Concerning Various Topics
  - Talks/Reflections by Hartman, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Talks/Thoughts by Hartman concerning Bethe and Corson (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Notes taken by Hartman (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Notes/Diary on work (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Report on summer work, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Report on summer work, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Notebook, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Notes concerning Optics (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence concerning CHESS, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Plans concerning the Synchrotron and CHESS (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Plans - Synchrotron, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Plans - Synchrotron, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Synchrotron notes (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Synchrotron notes, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Synchrotron articles and correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Radar - articles and correspondence, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Vacuum Furnace Brazing of Windows - notes, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Plans - concerning the Cyclotron plaque (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Sketches by Hartman (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Krumhansl Report (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Notebooks from courses Hartman took in Physics and Math at Cornell (Box 2)
- Series V. Photographs and Exhibit Material
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Photographs of Prof. Siegel's Electron Microscope Lab, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Photocopies of archival material used in exhibits (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Exhibit material used for Physical Review Centenary in Washington, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 49)